나 왔어
혼인무효신고는 잘 끝났어?
Did everything go okay
with the annulment?
그럼, 당연하지
깨끗이 해결했어
No problems.
It's all taken care of.
Ross, thank you.
로스, 고마워
Want to go see a movie?
너희들 영화 보러 갈래?
그래, 좋지
Yeah, why not?
- 나 스웨터 입고 올게
- 그래
I'll get my sweater.
Want to hear something weird?
재미있는 얘기 듣고 싶니?
Always.
두말하면 잔소리
I didn't get the annulment.
나 혼인무효신고 안 했다
What?
- 뭐?
- 우린 아직 부부야
We're still married.
Don't tell Rachel. See you later.
레이첼한텐 비밀이야
나중에 보자
Do you have any gum?
혹시 껌 있어?
그래
Wait! Wait! Ross, can I just
talk to you for just a second?
잠깐만, 로스
나랑 얘기 좀 할까?
피비, 이러다 늦겠어
We'll be late for the movie.
There's a cab. Taxi!
저기 차 온다, 택시!
That's great.
세상에, 타이밍 절묘하다
잘 가라
What timing! My God, huh?
There you go.
We're gonna walk.
It's right at the Angelika.
걸어갈 거야
요 앞 안젤리카거든
안젤리카, 출발합시다!
The Angelika! Go! Go!
You didn't get the annulment?!
혼인무효신청을 안 했어?
I know.
그렇다니까
로스
하려고 했는데 변호사사무실에
가니까 이런 소리가 들리잖아
I tried, but when I got to
my lawyer's office, all I heard was:
"Three divorces! Three divorces!"
세 번째 이혼, 세 번째 이혼...
Yes, in that high voice.
맞아, 그 새된 목소리
내 묘비에 이렇게 새길까?
'로스 겔러, 세 번 이혼하다'
I just don't want my tombstone to read:
"Ross Geller: Three Divorces."
Don't worry about that. Your tombstone
can say whatever you want.
걱정도 팔자다, 묘비야
원하는 대로 쓰면 되지
It can say,
"Ross Geller: Good at Marriage."
예를 들어...
'로스 겔러, 결혼전문가'
You know? Mine's gonna say,
"Phoebe Buffay: Buried Alive."
알아? 난 이렇게 쓸 거야
'피비 부페이, 생매장되다'
All I know is, I can't have
another failed marriage.
어쨌거나 이번에 또
결혼에 실패할 순 없어
그럼 여자애를 속여서
결혼하겠다는 거야?
So you're gonna be married to
a girl who doesn't even know about it?
참, 숙녀지
미안해
Woman. Sorry.
알았어, 아직 완전히
결정된 건 아니니까
Okay, so I don't have it all
worked out quite yet.
제발 레이첼한테는
얘기하지 마
Just don't say anything to Rachel.
Rachel is one of my closest friends.
레이첼은 둘도 없는 친구야
But being the only one that knows
about this makes me feel special. Okay.
근데 비밀을 혼자만 아는 것도
기분 괜찮구나, 좋았어
여기 세워요
Okay, stop, stop! Phoebe?
- 피비!
- 이게 누구야?
Hey, Rach!
What was that?
왜 그런 거야?
미안, 좀 헷갈렸어
Sorry. Mix-up.
How was the movie?
영화는 어땠니?
I haven't seen it yet.
아직 못 봤어, 로스...
그럼 서둘러야지
안젤리카, 출발!
You'd better hurry.
The Angelika! Go!
안 돼!
The One Where Ross Hugs Rachel
When I move in,
can I get a gumball machine?
우리 같이 살게 되면
검볼 기계 들여놔도 될까?
Of course. Joey wouldn't
let you have one?
물론이지
조이가 반대할 것 같아서?
No, when it comes to sweets,
he's surprisingly strict.
단물 빠지는 거에 대해선
지나치게 엄격하거든
Did you tell him you're moving out?
조이한테 어떻게
말할지 생각해봤어?
아니, 몇 번 시도는 했지
'조이, 나... '
No, I keep trying.
And I can get out, "Joey, I have to.."
Then I lose my nerve and I finish
with, "go to the bathroom."
하지만 결론은 늘 이래
'화장실 갔다 올게'
He may think I'm sick.
내가 어디 아픈 줄 알 걸
I have to tell Rachel, but....
We just gotta get it over with.
나도 레이첼한테
말해야 되는데...
피해서 될 일은 아니니까
Next time we see them,
we'll just tell them. That's it.
다음에 걔들 보면 무조건
말하기로 하자, 알았지?
자기 명령만 따르면
다 잘 해결되는 거야?
That's how it'll work now?
You'll just order me around?
-Pretty much.
-All right.
- 그렇지 뭐
- 알았어
- 모니카
- 왔어?
Hey, man, you feeling better?
너 좀 괜찮냐?
뭐 그냥...
조이, 너한테 할말이 있어
We have something to tell you.
Oh, my God!
맙소사, 너 임신했구나
You're pregnant!
No!
아냐
- 아니지?
- 아냐
아니고말고
Look, Joe, here's the thing.
조이, 사실은...
Monica and I have decided
to live together, here.
모니카랑 같이 살기로 했어
이 집에서...
I'm gonna be moving out, man.
나 이쪽으로 옮겨 올 거야
정말 잘됐다, 축하해
I'm really happy for you guys.
Congratulations. See you later.
- 이따 보자
- 얘, 조이
조이, 너 괜찮니?
Are you okay?
그럼, 가봐야 돼
일자리가 생겼거든
I gotta go. I've got an acting job.
Like you'd believe that.
어차피 믿지도 않겠지만
This sucks!
말도 안 돼
I'll be across the hall.
And I promise you...
그래봤자 복도 건너편이잖아
약속하지, 모니카랑 깨지면
바로 다시 들어갈게
the minute Monica and I break up,
I'm moving right back in.
Maybe that's now.
지금 하는 건 어때?
좋아, 얘들아
If you're gonna move in with him...
저 녀석이랑 꼭 같이 살겠다면
난 진실을 알려줄 의무가 있어
I feel it is my responsibility
to tell you the truth about him.
He's a terrible roommate. Terrible.
쟤 진짜 형편없는 룸메이트야
그러니까 끄떡하면...
He forgets to....
늘 그렇다니까
He always, he always....
Who am I kidding?
He's the best roommate!
무슨 소리야
최고의 룸메이트인데
-Hey, Phoebe.
-Hey.
- 안녕, 피비
- 왔어?
Oh, look, here's an article about people
who marry people and don't tell them.
상대도 모르게 결혼하는
사람들 기사가 났어
-Really?
-Yeah, I'm reading Ross Geller Magazine.
- 정말?
- 그래, '로스 겔러 잡지'거든
- 피비
- 어서 와
Have you seen Rachel?
- 레이첼 봤어?
- 아니, 왜?
-No, why?
-I have some exciting news.
좋은 소식이 있어
너 임신했구나
You're pregnant.
No!
아냐
Chandler and I are moving in together.
챈들러랑 같이 살기로 했어
Oh, that's good!
그거 잘됐다
But if you were pregnant,
what would you name it? Hint, Phoebe.
근데 아이 가지면 이름은
뭐라고 할래? 힌트는 피비야
- 왔니?
- 오빠
What's up?
무슨 일이야?
저기...
Chandler and I are moving in together.
나 챈들러랑 같이 살 거야
Oh, my God.
세상에
Oh, my little sister
and my best friend...
내 여동생과
내 가장 친한 친구가...
shacking up.
살림 벌이는구나
That's great. That's great.
그래, 잘됐다
Guys, I'm happy too.
얘들아, 나도 기뻐
그래, 이리 와
Okay, come here.
Big day, huh? People moving in.
People getting annulled.
오늘 무슨 날이니?
누군 동거 시작하고
누군 혼인 취소하고
I gotta go find Rachel.
난 레이첼을 찾아봐야겠다
If you see her, give her some really
bad news, so mine doesn't seem so bad.
걔 보면 진짜 나쁜 소식부터
전해 줘, 내 얘긴 살짝 묻히게
그래, 잘 가
레이첼한테 나쁜 소식이라...
Something bad to tell Rachel.
Bad news for Rachel.
What could that be?
레이첼한테 나쁜 소식이 뭘까?
Can you just lay off, please?
너무 그러지 마라
My life is an embarrassment. I should
just go live under somebody's stairs.
안 그래도 창피해 죽겠어
쥐구멍에라도 들어가고 싶다
It's not that big a deal.
You'll have been divorced three times.
그게 무슨 대수야?
세 번 이혼한 남자는
다른 여자 만나면 안 돼?
You'll have a life, you'll date..
그럼, 못하지
No, I won't. I'll be at the bottom
of the dating barrel now.
이제 내 인생에 데이트는 없어
The only guys below me
will be Four-Divorce Guy...
나보다 비참한 사람은
네 번 이혼한 남자나...
살인자...
Murderer Guy...
and geologists.
지질학자 정도지
Ross, you're being ridiculous.
You are cute and smart and sweet.
로스, 그런 말하지 마
넌 인물 좋고 똑똑하고 자상해
That is much more important
than three stupid divorces.
세 번 이혼한 건
그렇게 중요하지 않아
그럼 넌 세 번 이혼한
남자랑 사귄 적 있어?
Have you dated anyone
who's been divorced three times?
That's not fair. Most guys that have
been divorced three times are 60.
그렇게 비교하면 안 되지
세 번 정도 이혼했으면
보통 환갑 나이잖아
You're young.
넌 젊어
맞아, 난 젊지
That's true, I am young.
그렇다
Well....
Nobody cares about this except you.
너 말고는 아무도 신경 안 써
This embarrassment thing is
all in your head.
창피하다는 것도
너 혼자 생각이고
-Here, I'll show you. Come here.
-What?
내가 보여줄게
- 이리 와
- 왜?
Hi. My friend Ross is about to be
divorced for the third time.
안녕하세요
내 친구 로스가
세 번째로 이혼하게 되는데
But wouldn't you date him?
만나줄 수 있겠죠?
여기서 잠시 기다리면
로스 녀석을 데려오죠
And if you wait right here,
I'll go get Ross.
Thought you were Rachel.
레이첼인 줄 알았어
What gave me away?
정체가 폭로됐군
이제 진짜로 얘기할 거야
I gotta tell her.
오빠랑 피비한테는 말했고
이제 레이첼만 남았어
I told Ross and Phoebe.
She's the only one left.
그럼 다 아는 거네
이젠 기정사실이야
It's official.
We're moving in together.
No turning back.
Are you scared? Are you?!
돌이킬 수 없어
두렵나? 어?
No.
아니
That was my scariest voice.
You're brave.
제일 무서운 목소리였는데
자기 너무 용감해
- 얘들아
- 어서 와
The worst day.
끔찍한 하루였어
You're finally making progress at work,
then your boss calls you Racquel.
이제 좀 다닐 만하다 싶더니
부장이 날 더러 '라켈'이래
난 4년 동안 동료들이
'샬라랍'이라고 하더라
Listen, for the first four years
of my work, everybody called me....
-Seriously.
-I believe you.
- 진짜야
- 믿어줄게
It was in the middle of a meeting,
so no one wants to correct her.
간부회의 도중이라
그냥 넘어갔더니
So everyone's calling me Racquel.
나중엔 다들 '라켈'이래
By the end of the day, the mailroom
guys were calling me Rocky.
퇴근할 때쯤엔 메일룸 직원이
'록키'라고 하더라
Well, I still think you're
very, very nice and very pretty.
누가 뭐래도 넌 착하고 예뻐
What?
뭐?
All yours, babe.
그냥 자기가 해라
레이첼, 잠깐만...
Have a seat.
앉아봐
저기 있잖아
Listen, Chandler and I...
챈들러랑 나...
같이 살기로 했어
are going to live together.
Here.
이 집에서
Oh, my God.
세상에
That's so great!
너무 멋지다
정말 잘됐다, 얘
I'm so happy for you guys!
Really?
진심이야?
어쩜 나한테 물어볼
생각을 다 하고
And that was so sweet of you to ask.
이럴 수가, 셋이서
살면 너무 신나겠다
The three of us are gonna have
such a good time living together!
Yes, we are.
그렇겠지
그리고 챈들러!
Chandler, you'll have to watch
those long showers you take...
아침에 샤워는 짧게 끝내
라켈이 지각하면 안 되거든
because you know
Racquel can't be late.
- 레이첼...
- 앞으론 조심할 거야
He'll work on that.
이런 경사가 있다니
This is so exciting!
Come and knock on our door
문을 두드리세요
그대를 기다릴게요
We'll be waiting for you
See? Once you know the stories,
it's not that bad.
어때요, 사연을 듣고 보니
이해가 되죠?
First marriage: Wife's hidden
sexuality. Not my fault.
첫 번째는 아내의 성적 취향
때문인데 내 잘못이 아니에요
두 번째는 식장에서
이름을 잘못 말한 건데
Second marriage:
Said the wrong name at the altar.
A little my fault.
약간은 내 잘못이죠
Third marriage: They shouldn't
let you get married...
세 번째 결혼은...
얼굴에 낙서까지 하고 나타난
고주망태 두 사람을 결혼시킨
when you're drunk
and have writing on your face.
네바다 주의 잘못이에요
Nevada's fault.
So what do you think, ladies?
Who wouldn't want to date him?
자, 여러분 생각은 어때요?
이 남자한테 관심이 안 가요?
The divorces don't bother me.
I'd date him.
이혼경력은 괜찮으니까
사귈 수도 있지만
현재 유부남이잖아요
But not while he's still married.
And you, wouldn't you want to date?
그럼 댁은요?
사귀고 싶지 않아요?
지금 만나는 남자는 없어요
I'm not dating at all anymore.
I was only dating guys
that were bad for me.
여태 사귀던 남자들은
내 짝이 아니었거든요
So I decided that..
- 그 문제부터 정리하고...
- 됐어요, 시끄러워요
Good. Good. Whatever.
And you, Meg?
당신은요, 메그?
Well, I don't care about
the divorces, either.
나도 이혼경력은 상관없지만
But I wouldn't date him.
사귈 마음은 없네요
평상시엔 이렇게
땀 많이 안 흘려요
Normally, he doesn't sweat this much.
It's just that he's obviously
still in love with this Rachel girl.
아무리 봐도 레이첼이란
여자를 사랑하고 있어요
What?
뭐요?
She said, "He's obviously still
in love with this Rachel girl."
아무리 봐도 레이첼이란
여자를 사랑하고 있대
말도 안 돼요
This is crazy. I mean, yes,
Rachel is my good friend.
물론 레이첼은 좋은 친구고
전에 사랑했던 여자지만
And I have loved her in the past...
지금은 그냥
내 아내일 뿐이에요
but now, she is just my wife.
Phoebe, will you help me out here?
피비, 뭐라고 좀 해봐
결혼했을 때는
사랑한 거 아냐?
Well, I thought you loved her
when you married her.
우린 취해 있었어
We were drunk! I would've married
Joey with that amount of alcohol.
그만큼 술을 마셨으면
조이랑도 결혼했겠다
야! 조이 트리비아니가
그렇게 우습게 보여?
You could do a lot worse
than Joey Tribbiani!
미안하지만 그건 오해예요
I'm sorry, but you guys are wrong.
I just don't want
to be divorced three times.
난 그냥 세 번이나
이혼하는 게 싫을 뿐이에요
네, 이혼하기 싫다는 핑계로
레이첼을 잡아두려는 거예요
Now he's using
this three-divorces reason...
because he wants to stay married
to her because he loves her.
걔를 사랑하니까
I must say, well done. Bravo, Meg.
정말 잘했어요
브라보, 메그
그래, 좋아
Fine. If this is what you think,
forget about...
그렇게 생각한다면
이혼 따위 겁날 게 뭐야
the whole three-divorce thing.
당장 변호사 찾아가서
이 결혼 취소하겠어, 됐지?
I'll go to my lawyer's office right now
and get this marriage annulled.
레이첼은 내게 아무 의미 없어
She means nothing to me.
Nothing!
쥐뿔도 아니라고요!
성격까지 이상한 것 같아서
더 만나기가 싫어지네요
Okay, now I wouldn't date you
because you seem a little creepy.
I am so attracted to him right now.
난 지금이 더 입맛 당기는 걸
When will we tell Rachel
what actually will happen?
레이첼한테는 언제
사실대로 말할 거야?
Soon.
곧 할 거야
I just couldn't before.
You saw how upset Joey got.
조이 반응을 보고서도
쉽게 말이 나오겠어?
I couldn't do it.
She's my best friend.
가장 친한 친구한테
차마 못할 짓이잖아
조이도 내 가장 친한 친구야
Joey's my best friend.
I'm not your best friend?
내가 가장 친한 친구 아냐?
넌 방금...
You just said..
Of course you're my best friend.
물론 네가 가장 친한 친구지
- 하여간 레이첼한테 얘기해
- 알았어
Would you tell Rachel?
All right. At least I'm prepared.
- 준비 좀 하고
- 그래
Oh, yes.
- 왜 이래
- 아야, 아야
너 줄 거 아냐
네가 맘 상했니?
-They're not for you. Are you upset?
-I am now.
이젠 그래
Hey, roomie.
안녕, 룸메이트
Okay, bye.
그래, 잘 있어라
레이첼
There's something important
I have to tell you.
아주 중요한 얘기가 있어
너 임신했지
Are you pregnant?
아니, 아무래도
이 셔츠 버려야겠다
No, but I'm throwing this shirt away.
I think there was a little
misunderstanding before.
전에 내 얘기를
좀 오해한 것 같아서
이 집에서 챈들러랑
같이 살겠다고 한 건...
When I said that Chandler and I
wanted to live together...
we meant alone together.
둘이서만 살겠다는 뜻이었어
맙소사
Oh, my God. That's funny.
I can't believe I did that.
미치겠네
내가 바보짓을 했구나
아냐, 이건 내 잘못이야
확실하게 말을 못했으니까
No, sweetie. You know what?
This is my fault.
I wasn't clear.
I'm really sorry.
정말 미안하다
들어봐
Listen, you take as much time
as you need to move out, okay?
서둘러 나갈 필요는 없어
느긋하게 생각해
There's absolutely no rush.
Okay.
알았어
그래
Don't you want a cookie?
과자 안 먹을래?
Sure.
좋지
Thanks.
고마워
티슈도 줄까?
Do you need a tissue?
- 모니카, 이거 어디서 났니?
- 내가 만들었어
-Where did you get these?
-I made them.
정말 맛있다, 얘
Oh, God, they're so yummy!
이건 누구 거지?
-Okay, whose is this?
-That's mine.
내 거다
- 그럼 이건?
- 그것도
-And what about this? Whose is this?
-That's mine.
Okay, whose dishwashing soap is this?
그렇다면 이 세제는?
That was here when we moved in.
이사 올 때부터 있던 거야
어쩐지 좀 찐하더라
Oh, I guess it really is concentrated.
It's gonna be weird when I come home
and you're not here.
집에 왔는데 네가 없으면
좀 이상할 거 같다
No more Joey and Chan's.
조이와 챈의 집도 없고
J와 C의 집도 없어
No more J and C's.
Want to go to Joey and Chandler's?
Can't. It's not there.
'조이랑 챈들러 집에 갈래?'
'안 돼, 그런 집 없어'
I'll be across the hall.
We can still do all the same stuff.
바로 건너편이잖아
달라질 건 없어
그래도 한밤중에 일어나서
We won't be able to have
those long talks at night...
서로의 감정과 미래에 대해
긴 대화를 나눌 순 없잖아
about our feelings and the future.
Not once did we do that.
그런 적 한 번도 없는데?
Don't you remember that night,
it was late and I was feeling sick...
언젠가 늦은 밤에
내가 좀 아팠는데
and you said
I would feel better tomorrow?
네가 그랬잖아
'내일은 나을 거야'
Oh, yeah. I remember that.
그랬구나
글쎄...
I don't know.
I'm just gonna miss living with you.
함께 살던 때가 그리울 거야
그래, 나도
Yeah, me too, man.
- 저건 뭐지?
- 진짜 메스껍다
-What the hell is that?
-That's disgusting.
- 얘들아
- 어서 와
I told Rachel that it's just
gonna be the two of us.
방금 레이첼한테
둘이서만 살 거라고 했어
Oh, yeah? Well, how'd she take it?
그래? 반응은 어때?
Really well.
괜찮더라, 그래
Surprisingly well.
내가 놀랄 정도로
She didn't cry.
She wasn't angry or sad.
울지도 않고 화도 안 내고
슬퍼하지도 않아
And you're upset because you
didn't make your best friend cry?
가장 친한 친구를
못 울려서 심통난 거야?
All I'm asking for is
a little emotion.
최소한의 감정은
보여줄 수 있잖아
Is that too much to ask
after six years?
우린 6년이나 함께 살았어
What, are Rachel and l
not as close as you guys?
레이첼이랑 내가
너희들보다 못하니?
I mean, did we not have as much fun?
Don't I deserve a few tears?
우린 즐겁게 안 지냈어?
눈물 몇 방울 흘리면 안 돼?
조이는 눈이 퉁퉁
붓도록 울었잖아
When we told Joey,
he cried his eyes out.
야!
I did not cry my eyes out!
누가 눈이 퉁퉁 붓도록 울어
이건 한 시대의 끝이잖아
Come on, it's like the end of an era.
No more J-Man and Channy's!
J맨과 채니의 집이 사라졌어
Okay, I gotta ask, who calls us that?
도대체 누가 우릴
그렇게 부르는데?
You got married again?
또 결혼을 하셨다고요?
Yes.
네
So that's your second marriage
in two years?
그럼 2년 동안 두 번이군요
Yes. Second in two years.
네, 2년 동안 두 번이죠
다 합해서 세 번이고
Third, overall.
I have been a divorce attorney
for 23 years...
23년간 이 일을 했지만
and never have I had
so much business from one client.
이렇게 많은 의뢰를 한
고객은 선생이 처음입니다
Why don't you tell me what happened?
어떻게 된 건지
한번 들어볼까요?
Basically, Rachel and I were
in Vegas, and we got drunk.
레이첼과 제가 라스베가스에
가서 술에 취했습니다
I'm sorry, is this the same Rachel
whose name you said...
죄송하지만 두 번째 결혼식 때
말했던 그 레이첼 말입니까?
at the altar
in the second marriage?
Yes, yes, yes.
네, 맞습니다
But I do not love her.
하지만 레이첼을
사랑하진 않아요
That's better then.
그럼 다행이군요
술 때문에 실수한 거예요
취소하고 싶습니다
This was just a drunken mistake,
and I need to get it annulled.
알겠습니다
I see.
Have you considered therapy?
정신과치료를
생각해보셨나요?
I think just the annulment for today.
오늘은 그냥 혼인만 취소하죠
-There are some forms to fill out.
-Easy.
- 서류 몇 장 작성하시고
- 그야 쉽죠
We'll need witnesses who can testify
that you were not of sound mind.
당시 상황을 증언해줄
사람도 필요합니다
No problem.
문제없죠
그리고 당사자 두 분이
법정에 출두해야 합니다
We'll need you and Rachel
to testify before a judge.
There's no way to do this without her?
저 혼자서는 안 될까요?
벌써 해결했다고
얘기를 해버려서
Because I kind of already told her
it was taken care of.
Of course you did.
물론 그러셨겠죠
Look, you can't get an annulment
unless you and Rachel are both there.
두 분이 출두하지 않으면
무효신청은 불가합니다
What about someone
who looks like Rachel?
그럼 레이첼이랑
닮은 사람은 어떨까요
I will think about the therapy.
정신과치료를 생각해보죠
- 왔니?
- 그래
So I was thinking that maybe we
should start dividing up our stuff.
지금부터 슬슬 각자의
물건을 챙기는 게 어떨까?
Okay.
그래
No point in dragging it out.
질질 끌 필요 없잖아
Dragging out the long process
of you moving out...
어차피 넌 여기서 나가야 되고
우린 같이 살 수가 없는데
and us not living together anymore.
알았어
좋아
- 레이첼
- 응?
이건 어때?
누가 가질까?
What about this? Who gets this?
I don't know if I want it because
it might be too many memories.
추억이 너무 많이 담겨서
가슴 아픈 물건인데
-What is that?
-I don't know.
- 이게 뭐야?
- 나도 몰라
레이첼?
How about this?
I want you to have the big plate.
이 쟁반은 어때?
너한테 줄게
Wow, Monica, thanks.
I love this plate.
정말 이래도 되니?
맘에 들긴 하지만
Something to remember me by.
날 기억해달라는 거야
Mon, you're not dying.
I'm just moving out.
누가 죽는 것도 아니잖아
그냥 이사 나가는 거야
We're gonna see each other
all the time.
매일 만날 건데 뭐
But still, it's a big change.
하지만...
많이 변할 거야
한 시대의 끝이거든
The end of an era, you might say.
안 그래?
Are you okay? You're not blinking.
너 괜찮니?
눈도 안 깜빡거리고
I'm fine. I was thinking about
how it's an end of an era.
괜찮아, 그냥 한 시대의
끝이란 생각이 들어서
Oh, all right.
그렇구나
But I gotta say, I don't think
six years counts as an era.
그래도 6년을 한 시대로
보기엔 무리가 있다
특별한 기간이었다면
시대라고 할 수 있어
An era is defined as
a significant period of time.
It was significant for me.
Maybe it wasn't significant to you!
나한테는 특별했는데
너한텐 특별하지 않았구나
-What is the matter with you?
-What is the matter with you?!
너 대체 왜 이래?
너야말로 왜 이래?
어쩜 그렇게 담담해?
Why aren't you more upset?
Aren't you gonna be sad
that we're not living together?
우리가 헤어지는데
슬프지도 않아?
Aren't you gonna miss me at all?
내가 보고 싶지 않겠어?
Monica, all right.
But don't get mad at me.
모니카, 알았어
듣고 화내지 마
It's just a little hard to believe.
사실 난 믿어지지 않아
What's hard to believe?
뭐가 안 믿어져?
너희들이 이런 일을
벌인다는 게
I mean, it's you guys.
You do this kind of stuff, you know?
알잖아, 라스베가스에서도
결혼한다더니 취소하고...
You were gonna get married in Vegas,
and then you backed out.
I'm not upset because I don't see you
going through with it. I'm sorry.
이 일도 긴가민가해서
실감이 안 나, 미안해
레이첼...
It's going to happen.
정말 그렇게 될 거야
Chandler will move in here.
챈들러가 이 집에 들어와
-But I..
-I know, just let me finish, okay?
- 하지만 난...
- 잠깐, 끝까지 들어
This isn't something that we just
impulsively decided to do in Vegas.
라스베가스에서처럼
충동적인 결정이 아냐
This is something
that we both really want.
둘 다 진정으로 원하는 거야
And it is going to happen.
정말 그렇게 한다니까
It is?
그래?
Really?
정말?
Yeah, sweetie.
그렇다니까
You mean, we're not gonna
live together anymore?
그럼... 우린 이제
떨어져서 살아야 돼?
그래
세상에...
Oh, my God.
I'm gonna miss you so much.
- 네가 보고 싶을 거야
- 나도
I'm gonna miss you.
I mean, it's the end of an era!
- 이건 한 시대의 끝이야
- 그렇다니까!
I know!
-Okay, bye.
-Oh, no.
- 안녕, 잘 있어
- 이런 맙소사...
So did you get the annulment?
취소는 잘 했어?
-I couldn't.
-I knew it. Because you love Rachel.
못했다
거봐, 넌 레이첼을
사랑한다니까
It's not that.
Annulments are more complicated..
그런 게 아니라
생각보다 절차가 복잡해
사랑 때문에 복잡하겠지
Complicated because of the love.
I do not love Rachel.
난 레이첼을 사랑하지 않아
I'm telling her
about the whole thing...
사실대로 말하고 가능한 한
빨리 이 결혼을 취소할 거야
so we can get this marriage
annulled as fast as possible.
걔를 사랑한다면
내가 이럴 수 있을까?
Would I do that if I loved her?
I've never been more convinced
of your love for her.
더더욱 너의 사랑을
확신하게 됐어
I do not have feelings
for Rachel, okay?
난 레이첼한테 아무런
감정도 없어, 알았냐?
Oh, what's wrong?
왜 그러고 있어?
Monica and Chandler are
moving in here...
모니카랑 챈들러가
진짜 같이 살 거래
and I have to move out
and everything is changing.
난 이사를 나가고
모든 게 변할 거야
Oh, my God, come here, come here.
It's okay.
저런, 이리 와
괜찮아, 다 잘될 거야
Everything's gonna be okay.
-Thank you.
-Of course.
고마워
별말을 다 한다
So Ross and Rachel got married.
그럼 로스랑
레이첼도 결혼하고
Monica and Chandler
almost got married.
모니카랑 챈들러도
곧 결혼할 거고
You think we should hook up?
우리 둘도 엮어볼까?
Oh, we do.
좋은 생각인데
아직은 안 돼
But not just yet.
Really? Well, when?
정말?
언제 되는데?
좋아
어디 보자
Well, first Chandler and Monica
will get married...
먼저 챈들러랑 모니카는
결혼하고 큰 부자가 되지만
and be filthy rich, by the way.
But it won't work out.
오래 못 가서 깨져
- 저런...
- 불행이지
I know.
Then I'll marry Chandler
for the money.
그럼 내가 챈들러의
돈을 노리고 결혼하지
And you'll marry Rachel
and have the beautiful kids.
그리고 넌 레이첼과 결혼해서
예쁜 애들을 낳는 거야
좋고...
Great.
But then we ditch them
and we get married.
그 다음에 걔들을 차버리고
우리가 결혼하는 거지
We'll have Chandler's money
and Rachel's kids.
챈들러의 돈과 레이첼의
아이들은 우리 차지야
Getting custody will be easy
because of Rachel's drinking problem.
레이첼의 음주벽 때문에
양육권 뺏는 건 일도 아냐
참, 로스는 어떻게 되지?
What about Ross?
I don't want to go
into the whole thing.
이런 말까지 하고 싶진 않지만
But we have words and I kill him.
내가 죽였다는 소문이 있어